Team-building exercises have become popular for managers trying to increase organisational and team harmony and productivity.
团队建设活动已在管理者中很受欢迎，他们力图借此提升组织和团队的和谐度与生产率。
Unfortunately many employees resent compulsory bonding and often regard these exercises as a nuisance.
遗憾的是，许多员工反感被迫去增进彼此的感情，还常常把这些活动视为麻烦事。
A paper published this week by University of Sydney researchers in Social Networks has reported participants’ feelings about team-building interventions, revealing ethical implications in forcing employees to take part.
悉尼大学的研究人员本周在《社会网络》期刊上发表了一篇论文，报告了参与者对团队建设干预措施的感受，揭示出强迫员工参与所涉及的伦理问题。
“Many people see team-building activities as a waste of time, so we decided to look in more depth at what’s behind this,” said the paper’s lead researcher, Dr Peter Matous.
“许多人把团队建设活动看作浪费时间，所以我们决定更深入地探究这背后的原因，”论文的首席研究员彼得·马图斯博士说。
“Teams are formed, combined and restructured.
“团队经历组建、合并与重组。
Staff are relocated and office spaces redesigned.
员工调换办公地点，办公空间重新设计。
All this is done with the aim of improving workplace efficiency, collaboration and cohesion.
所有这一切，都是为了提升工作场所的效率、协作水平和凝聚力。
But does any of this work?” said Dr Matous.
但这些做法真有哪一项管用吗？”马图斯博士说。
The study found that team-building exercises which focused on the sharing of and intervening in personal attitudes and relationships between team members were considered too heavy-handed and intrusive, although the researchers say some degree of openness and vulnerability is often necessary to make deep, effective connections with colleagues.
研究发现，有些团队建设活动侧重于分享和干预团队成员的个人态度以及成员之间的关系，这类活动被认为过于强硬，也过于干涉私事；不过研究人员表示，要与同事建立深入而有效的联系，往往需要在一定程度上敞开心扉、展露自己的脆弱。
“Some participants were against team-building exercises because they were implicitly compulsory.
“一些参与者反对团队建设活动，因为这些活动是变相强制的。
They didn’t welcome management’s interest in their lives beyond their direct work performance,” said Matous.
他们不乐意管理层关注自己直接工作表现以外的生活，”马图斯说。
“Many people don’t want to be forced into having fun or making friends, especially not on top of their busy jobs.
“许多人不想被迫去玩乐或交朋友，尤其不想在本已繁忙的工作之外还要这样做。
They feel management is being too nosy or trying to control their lives too much.”
他们觉得管理层太爱打听，或是试图过多地控制他们的生活。”
In this study the researchers recommended a self-disclosure approach where participants were guided through a series of questions that allowed them to increasingly disclose personal information and values.
在这项研究中，研究人员推荐了一种自我表露的方法：在引导下，参与者依次回答一系列问题，这些问题让他们能够越来越多地透露个人信息和价值观。
The method is well-tested and has been shown to increase interpersonal closeness.
这种方法经过了充分检验，已被证明能增进人际亲密感。
However, to be successful it must be voluntary.
不过，这种方法要想成功，就必须出于自愿。
The researchers said there are numerous schools of thought that propose differing psychological methods for strengthening relationships.
研究人员说，有众多学派提出各不相同的心理学方法来加强人际关系。
“With caution, many relational methods to improve teams and organisations can be borrowed from other fields.
“许多用于改善团队和组织的关系类方法，都可以谨慎地从其他领域借鉴过来。
The question is how to apply them effectively to strengthen an entire collective, which is more than just the sum of individual relationships,” said Dr Matous.
问题在于如何有效地运用这些方法来加强整个集体，而集体不仅仅是个体之间各种关系的总和，”马图斯博士说。